Personal information

Name / Surname Address

Telephone
Personal Email
Date of birth
Github profile

Paolo Scaramuzza

via Androna della Pergola 14 34170 Gorizia (GO), Italy

 $+39\ 3461724250$

paoscr@gmail.com

16 December, 1992

https://github.com/electricant

https://www.linkedin.com/in/paolo-scaramuzza



About

LinkedIn

I thrive on the challenges of the electronic engineering landscape. With 10 years of experience, I tackle complex engineering challenges with confidence and precision. I am also completing a Master's degree in Management Engineering, perfect for leading a project from specifications to reality.

Working Experience

2020 - 2022

Electronics Engineering Consultant

Provide solutions and guidance to clients navigating complex electronic design challenges (RF, High Speed PCB Design & system integration).

Oct. 2019 - present

Hardware RF application engineer at u-blox Italia S.p.A.

I undertake the design and release of demo boards for cellular modules, along with composing detailed documentation. Additionally, I provide support to customers in refining and validating their designs, and maintainin technical communication with business partners and the R&D department.

Oct. 2017 - May 2018

Internship at Infineon Technologies Villach, Austria

The internship was focused on the design and measurement of integrated $28\,\mathrm{GHz}$ power amplifiers for $5\mathrm{G}$ cellular networks.

Skills

Electronics

Analog, RF and Digital Electronics Design using Altium, Cadence Allegro & Virtuoso, ADS, KiCAD and LTSPICE.

Electromagnetic simulations with HFSS, ADS Momentum and Sonnet.

Prototyping & Testing

Analog/RF/mixed-signal circuits measurement and characterization. Device RF testing according to ETSI/3GPP/FCC standards.

Programming languages

C, C++, Perl, Python, R, MATLAB, and others.

Project & program management

Ensure the seamless execution of electronic engineering initiatives, from planning to delivery, while optimizing resources and mitigating risks.

Version Control Systems

Familiarity with version control tools like Git, SVN & Perforce for managing project files and collaborating with team members.

Marketing & business strategy

Expertise in innovation management, strategic planning, and market analysis.

Communication Skills

Effective communication skills for conveying technical concepts to stakeholders, team members, and collaborators.

Self-assessment $European\ level^{(*)}$

English German Slovene

Understanding		Speaking		Writing
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1 Proficient user				
A2 Basic user				
A1 Basic user				

^(*) Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

March 2011

Certificate in Advanced English (CAE)

Education

2022 - present

Master's degree in Management Engineering

University of Udine

Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2019

Ph.D. in Information Engineering, University of Padova

Topic: Fully-integrated Power Amplifiers for 5G Communications

(supervisor: Andrea Neviani, Andrea Bevilacqua)

Nov. 2018

During the Ph.D., was awarded at the **Huawei Italy University Challenge** in Pavia, aimed at inspiring research in Silicon Integrated Circuits for Analog, RF, mmWave and Optical transceivers

July 2017

Qualification test (esame di stato) for being a professional Engineer

2014 - 2016

Master's degree in Electronics Engineering (110/110 cum laude)

University of Padova, thesis title: "Project of a Class J Power Amplifier in Integrated Bipolar Technology"

June 2015

While studying for his M.Sc, received the Roberto Rocca Education Program scolarship for academic merit.

2011 - 2014

Bachelor's degree in Information Engineering (110/110)

University of Padova, thesis title: "A Study on the Efficiency of Integrated LC Oscillators for Ultra Wideband Impulse Radio Transmission"

2006 - 2011

Liceo Scientifico "Duca degli Abruzzi" in Gorizia

Publications

TCAS-I 2018

P. Scaramuzza, C. Rubino, M. Caruso, M. Tiebout, A. Bevilacqua, and A. Neviani

Class-J SiGe X-Band Power Amplifier Using a Ladder Filter-Based AM-PM Distortion Reduction Technique

ESSCIRC 2017

P. Scaramuzza, C. Rubino, M. Tiebout, M. Caruso, M. Ortner,

A. Neviani, and A. Bevilacqua

Class-AB and Class-J 22dBm SiGe HBT PAs for X-Band Radar Systems